over Christmas I made a chocolate orange
cheesecake I used the BBC good food
recipe here there was quite a bit left
because it was massive so I'm gonna use
it into my screen
[Music]
so yeah I had quite a bit of this
cheesecake left it was
chocolate orange flavor so it had a
cookie crumb base that had cocoa powder
in it I added the coke powder just you
know because I could and then you had
loads of orange zest in the actual
cheesecake itself it's a baked
cheesecake turned out really nice really
heavy very dense I I cut myself a
massive slice to start with it was way
too much
so we started to eat something realized
it was just too much to eat so we put
some in the freezer and I thought you
know what I will do something with this
ice cream wise and that is what this
video is about so let's see what I used
it for
so for the ice cream base we started
with our milk in the pan and turned on
the heat and as it was warming up we
added in the dextrose and our table
sugar got those nicely dissolved
when the milk came up about 50 degrees
Centigrade added in the cocoa powder
this is cocoa Berry Brut cocoa powder if
you're interested
and got that nicely combined before
finally adding in the useless milk
powder that doesn't want to dissolve and
eventually after 75 years it all became
Incorporated at that stage I took it off
the heat and put it in a container where
I finally added in the cream which
brings temperature down nice and quick
before popping it in the fridge
overnight
the next day I got some of the Frozen
cheesecake out and prepared a little bit
of Mozart liqueur and some double cream
along with a little mini blender we're
gonna get all this mixed together so
lots of chunks of the cheesecake again
this has got a cookie crumb chocolate
cookie crumb base and we're going to
start adding in our 30 to 50 mL of
chocolate liqueur you don't have to add
that if you don't want to just adds a
nice little Dimension to the flavor and
once again I forgot to turn the power on
and we're going to start blending this
up just keep on going you want it really
really smooth
finally adding in a little bit of double
cream if necessary just to loosen it
back up once it's done you're going to
pop on the table make sure you've got a
lovely cup of tea actually it's coffee
but you know I'm English and everyone
thinks English people drink tea I drink
coffee
we're gonna take it out of this
container put in two little containers
as you can see because our ice cream is
about to be churned
so the bases come out the fridge gonna
give it one final mix up make sure
everything is once again fully
emulsified and then we're going to pop
it in our ice cream machine Churn it as
normal this one didn't take long at all
it it took nine minutes in my machine
and that's a chocolate ice cream thing
so if you're interested in white
chocolate ice cream is different head
over to the chocolate ice cream series
and we talk about it there
so once your ice cream is churned you're
gonna forget that you've not got any
tubs ready and again I'm going to start
labeling them all up blah blah blah and
we're going to take some of our
digestive biscuits in the US Canada
you've got your graham cracker use those
wherever you are this is a semi-sweet
kit with a nice kind of dry flavor
you're going to break some of these up
and put those to the side now we're
going to start loading up the tubs now
this has take a nice scoop of your ice
cream out of your machine and then add
in a good dollop and that's a technical
term of your chocolate cheesecake add in
so that's a nice thick liquid and a
sprinkling of your biscuit crumb and
you'll repeat that over and over again
until you've filled up your tub
completely then you're going to put it
in the freezer overnight to home
[Music]
it's chucking it down rain out there so
if you can hear any noise Tippy tapa
that's the rain hitting the window this
is England welcome it rains 300 days of
the year here
the ice cream's out in the freezer it
went quite hard that's a again that's a
chocolate ice cream thing so don't be
afraid if it does let's get some scooped
up and see what it turned out like
[Music]
yeah the ice cream scooped reasonably
well not as soft as I'd like but it's a
chocolate ice cream thing it's the solid
increase by using cocoa powder it
increases the Solace to the point where
it makes it slightly harder to scoop you
can counter that with some dextrose
invert sugar you know you know glucose
or whatever
corn syrup honey if you really want to
go down that route
um something like that
which will lower the freezing point
again
but again you're looking at that balance
just take it out the freezer for
something like this you don't want to
really start playing with chocolate ice
cream it's one of the hardest ice cream
flavors to make really well but
it's got all the nice layers in there
let's see what it tastes like
[Music]
nice really nice orange flavor coming
through not overpoweringly so because
obviously it's just that add-in that's
got it
the cookie crumb throughout has a nice
kind of texture change which is good the
chocolate ice cream
the flavor of the cocoa Berry
Brut cocoa powder is quite nice it's not
my favorite but it's certainly a very
good quality cocoa powder so if you're
if you want to try something new and you
haven't tried that one give it a try
it's nice strong cocoa powder
good color I'd say the actual
cheesecake swirl let's call it that
I say the cheesecake swirl probably
needed a little bit more sugar I think
the inclusion of something like corn
syrup might have been beneficial
that would soften up a little bit more
because it's gone ever so slightly icy
but again it's not really a problem
because you're in control of that if
you've got some I'd say add some invert
sugar I'll put a little adjustment in
the recipe in the description below
of what I think might help there but
overall a really nice combo this is kind
of like a classic combo that you know
your Ben and Jerry's and Haagen-Dazs
would try and create a cheesecake swirl
with cookie crumb really nice
if you have cheesecake left over adjust
the recipe to suit so you know if you've
got a New York cheesecake that's you
know vanilla flavored do this with
vanilla there's vanilla good vanilla ice
cream with vanilla cheesecake swirl and
some Biscuit Crumbs would be really
really nice so so let me know if you
have tried you know a cheesecake swirl
in your ice cream before how did it turn
out hopefully this recipe is helpful for
some of you you can support the channel
on Kofi I'll put a link below that
really helps us buy some of the unusual
ingredients because we are not monetized
on YouTube at this point but as always
we really appreciate everyone coming on
the ice cream Journey
another good one I'm gonna eat tonight
thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe and we'll
see you next time
[Music]